Our buying Costa Rica have a house
juice. We don't have one, so I made one
up. I'm going to show you what I put in
it.
This is wild peanut. This is our
vanilla. This is our squash. We need
some limes.
These are bananas. That's a hibiscus.
That's a baby pineapple. Herba buena.
Herba buena. Herba buena. We need
[music] that. Them's oranges. We need a
ladder.
It's not going to work.
That worked. We got to get a couple more
of those.
I need a machete.
Let's wash it. Okay, to the sink.
Frog.
Oh my god. [music] And fast.
This is the trapiche. This is how you
work a trapiche. Yes. Stick it in there.
And then you got to This is
This is easier with two people or
animals.
You got it.
Turn this at the same time. Oh wait, we
forgot the bottle. Okay, bottle,
strainer,
bug. Okay.
This is how you work a trapiche. Okay?
And it squeezes the juice out. Look at
the juice. Can you see the juice?
Okay, it farts this out. That's it.
We could have used another stick. We
don't need any more.
Sorry. I need a coconut. Them's not
[music] big enough.
Third one.
Now I've got to make some juice.
Coconut, herba [music] buena, sugar
cane,
oranges, limes. We're going to take
this. We're going to take this. We're
going to put this juice in there.
Got it.
Cut.
The orange I'm [music] going to juice.
The limes are not going to juice. I'm
going to blend those up in a thing and
then strain them.
I need a knife.
I lied. That's not an orange, that's a
lemon.
We're going to put it in there anyways.
That's good.
Limes I'm going to [music] cut in
quarters.
I need a blender. We're just going to
blend this [music] whole the whole bunch
of it.
We're going to put this juice in there
with it.
Good. Now I'm going to take this and
we're going to strain all the
[music] out. Ooh, that smells good.
Okay.
I don't like that.
That's good. Now we take this juice.
Ooh, herba buena.
Leaves. You got to have a lot of herba
buena. I think this is why in Costa Rica
every [music] household has like one or
two ladies that are just permanently in
the kitchen because everything you make
here
takes so long to make.
Now we're going to
put
that stuff in there. Then we need water
[music] and ice.
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco, seis.
Ow. Water.
Blend it.
Drink it.
Mmm.
House juice. I don't know what everybody
else in Costa Rica makes their house
juice out of. We're just going in the
yard and grab a bunch of stuff, put it
in the blender, and then keep adding
stuff until [music] it tastes good. This
one turned out okay.